Finding Aid for A History of Michigan in Paintings, ca. 1964-1967
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
A History of Michigan in Paintings
circa 1964-1967
Thom, Robert A.
88574 UAm
25 photographs in 1 folder
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The prints were distributed by the Michigan Historical Commission through the John M. Munson Michigan History Fund.
The collection is open to research.
A History of Michigan in Paintings was a series of paintings commissioned by Michigan Bell Telephone Company to advance the knowledge of the State of Michigan's "colorful and exciting development." Robert Thom was the artist. F. Clever Bald wrote the accompanying text for the graphic reproductions of the paintings.
The prints are illustrative of significant moments in the history of Michigan from pre-history to World War II.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Automobiles--Michigan.; Cadillac, Antoine Laumet de Lamothe, 1658-1730.; Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866.; Detroit (Mich.)--Pictorial works.; Fort Michilimackinac (Mackinaw City, Mich.); Fort Mackinac (Mackinac Island, Mich.); Fur trade--Michigan.; Harvey, Charles Thompson, 1829-1912.; Houghton, Douglass, 1809-1845.; Indians of North America--Michigan.; Interiors--Schools.; Joliet, Louis, 1645-1700.; Kalamazoo (Mich.)--Pictorial works.; La Salle, Robert Cavelier, sieur de, 1643-1687.; Lansing (Mich.)--Pictorial works.; Lumber industry.; Marquette, Jacques, 1637-1675.; Marquette (Mich.)--Pictorial works.; Mason, Stevens Thomson, 1811-1843.; Michigan--Capital and capitol.; Michigan--History.; Perry, Oliver Hazard, 1785-1819.; Pictured Rocks (Mich.); Railroads--Michigan.; Saint Lusson, Simon François Daumont, sieur de, fl. 17th cent.; Sault Sainte Marie (Mich.)--Pictorial works.; Sault Sainte Marie Canal (Mich.); Ships--Great Lakes.; United States--History--War of 1812.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 24th (1862-1865); Willow Run Bomber Plant.
Contributors:
Bald, F. Clever (Frederick Clever), 1897-1970.; Michigan Historical Commission.; Michigan Bell Telephone Company.
- A History of Michigan in Paintings
  - Set 1
    - Before History: 10, 000 B.C. (Folder UAm)
    - Michigan Indians: Algonquin village about 1500 A.D. (Folder UAm)
    - Sieur de La Salle and the "Griffon": St. Ignace, August 27, 1679 (Folder UAm)
    - Massacre at Michilimackinac: June 2, 1763 (Folder UAm)
  - Set 2
    - Mme. Cadillac arrives at Detroit: October 1701 (Folder UAm)
    - Perry transfers to the "Niagara": September 10, 1813 (Folder UAm)
    - The Americans take over Fort Mackinac: September 1, 1796 (Folder UAm)
    - Lewis Cass expedition: May 25-September 23, 1820 (Folder UAm)
  - Set 3
    - Douglass Houghton finds copper: 1840 (Folder UAm)
    - The Capitol moves to Lansing: January 3, 1848 (Folder UAm)
    - Charles Harvey builds the locks:, 1853-1855 (Folder UAm)
    - Putting the world on wheels: 1913 (Folder UAm)
  - Set 4
    - When Pine was King:, 1840-1890 (Folder UAm)
    - The Detroit fire: June 11, 1805 (Folder UAm)
    - Furs-Trappers-Traders: 1660-1850 (Folder UAm)
    - The boy governor: July 24, 1831 (Folder UAm)
  - Set 5
    - Detroit-world port: 1965 (Folder UAm)
    - Joliet and Marquette: May 17, 1673 (Folder UAm)
    - The pageant of the Sault: June 14, 1671 (Folder UAm)
    - The one-room school: 1861 (Folder UAm)
  - Set 6
    - Michigan in the Civil War:, 1861-1865 (Folder UAm)
    - Michigan fever: 1836 (Folder UAm)
    - The iron horse: July 1837 (Folder UAm)
    - Riches underground: 1966 (Folder UAm)
    - Arsenal of Democracy: World War II (Folder UAm)